FELIPE MOBUS

personal information

Felipe Mobus, Brazilian

fmobus@gmail.com

https://github.com/fmobus

Munich, BY - Germany

https://fmob.us

education

04/2003 - 08/2008

BSc. Computer Science at UFRGS - Porto Alegre

Porto Alegre - Brazil

(Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul)

11/2006 - 10/2007

Exchange student at TU-Kaiserslautern

Kaiserslautern - Germany (Technische Universität Kaiserslautern)

professional experience

08/2019 - today

Software Engineer at Google.

Munich - Germany

03/2012 - 07/2019

Porto Alegre - Brazil Santiago - Chile Senior Consultant Developer at **ThoughtWorks**, tasked with leading diverse, high performance teams focused on delivering bespoke software for enterprise clients, across several different business domains, technologies, and platforms, leveraging the agile method to ensure quality and business value.

ThoughtWorks is a global consulting, advisory, and project delivery company best known for its contributions to agile methodologies.

Throughout my tenure at this company, I have worked with several business domains, including: publishing, education, air travel, insurance, financial planning, digital banking.

languages: java, kotlin, javascript, ruby, python, groovy frameworks: koin, spring, android, rails, sinatra, flask, react, react-native techniques: TDD, DDD, continuous integration, microservice architectures

11/2007 - 02/2012 05/2006 - 10/2006 Porto Alegre - Brazil Programmer at **Propus**, tasked with maintenance, support and development of several scripts and applications. Propus' main focus is outsourcing system administration tasks, with developers contributing in more complex cases.

technologies: python, ruby, php, postgres; mysql; asterisk

11/2006 - 10/2007 Kaiserslautern - Germany Undergraduate research assistant at **AG-DBIS** under Prof. Dr. Theo Härder. Tasked with the research, design and implementation of techniques for XML document summarization for the XTC project - a Java-based Native XML Database System. Technical report (also final BSc. Project) is available on-line 1

technologies: java; xml

page 1 of 2

_

available at https://fmob.us/tcc_fmobus.pdf

FELIPE MOBUS

01/2015 - 07/2015 12/2013 - 05/2014 02/2008 - 06/2008

(consultant) 10/2005 - 04/2006

Porto Alegre - Brazil

Developer at Associação Software Livre.Org (ASL). ASL is the NGO responsible for FISL, the largest free software conference in Latin America. Tasked with development, support, maintenance and operation of the systems used for attendants' registration during several editions of this conference

technologies: php, mysql, python, postgresql, javascript, mongodb

technologies, skills and competences

java / kotlin	Preferred language for backend solutions, usually employing spring framework; strong command of testing tools, decoupled design; past contact with Android environment; currently working on a kotlin project				
ruby	Used for large-scale projects at work, powered by popular frameworks like rails and sinatra . Great fan of the amazing rspec testing framework.				
javascript	Strong command of the language, including its modern babel-based incarnations; strong enthusiast of the react framework; recently worked in a react-native project				
python	Preferred language for quick projects and experiments; used in several projects in the past, especially with django and flask .				
devops	Experience with ansible , vagrant , and of course docker .				
TDD / BDD	Applied them both using junit, mockito, rspec , cucumber , jasmine and other tools.				
design	A big fan of microservice architecture , but always eager to discuss new ideas. Well-versed in UNIX principles and tools.				
functional	Can defend myself around haskell or elm , would love to use it more				

personal pet projects

(all code available on github - work in progress)

a simple solitary card game that is surprisingly complicated to win https://fmob.us/projects/git/corazones

language skills

	listening	reading	interaction	speaking	writing
portuguese	native	native	native	native	native
english	fluent	fluent	fluent	fluent	fluent
spanish	fluent	fluent	fluent	fluent	advanced
german	intermediate	intermediate	basic	basic	basic

about me

I regard myself as a responsible and proactive person, having being able to exercise my dedication in several different projects throughout my professional life. I consider myself open to new experiences, especially with regards to meeting new people and understanding different cultures.

I like to constantly exercise my analytical skills by dissecting real-world problems in our societies, and coming up with possible solutions, fostering better discussion of the subject, and

FELIPE MOBUS

hopefully inspiring others.

I am a great enthusiast of free software and open data movements, having worked as a volunteer for the former for several years, and doing my share of hacking around the latter. I believe that knowledge sharing and administrative transparency are essential tools for building societies that are both more efficient and more equitable.